<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  
  <title><![CDATA[Touching Research]]></title>
  <subtitle><![CDATA[Experimental Psychology]]></subtitle>
  <link href="//atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://touchingresearch.com//"/>
  <updated>2016-10-14T11:52:41.000Z</updated>
  <id>http://touchingresearch.com//</id>
  
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mandy Tjew A Sin]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Coursera course 'Improving Your Statistical Inferences']]></title>
    <link href="http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2016/10/14/coursera-course-improving-your-statistical-inferences/"/>
    <id>http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2016/10/14/coursera-course-improving-your-statistical-inferences/</id>
    <published>2016-10-14T11:44:08.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-14T11:52:41.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had to double-check, but it seems that I’ve neglected to write about taking the 2-day KLI course <a href="http://www.kurtlewininstituut.nl/teaching/program/content/?cid=289" target="_blank" rel="external">‘Designing Studies with High Informational Value’</a> back in September, 2015, held at the Vrije Universiteit. It was a very good course, and especially useful for graduate students and anyone who is contemplating a career in (psychological) science. The course was taught by Dr. Daniel Lakens of the Eindhoven University of Technology, and by Dr. Ellen Evers and Dr. Uri Simonsohn of The Wharton School, University of Pennsylvania. For me personally, it was an eye-opening and highly informative course (I did my first P-curve analyses on my own data during the lectures) and now the course is <a href="https://www.coursera.org/learn/statistical-inferences" target="_blank" rel="external">available on Coursera</a>. Since I’m setting up my research project here in Tuebingen during the week, I’m mostly enjoying it as a refresher course on the weekends.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>I had to double-check, but it seems that I’ve neglected to write about taking the 2-day KLI course <a href="http://www.kurtlewininstituut]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Setting up a hyperscanning project using NIRS in Tübingen, Germany]]></title>
    <link href="http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2016/10/06/setting-up-a-hyperscanning-project-using-nirs-in-tubingen-germany/"/>
    <id>http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2016/10/06/setting-up-a-hyperscanning-project-using-nirs-in-tubingen-germany/</id>
    <published>2016-10-06T07:44:30.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-07T07:59:33.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It’s already been a week since I’ve started working at the University of Tübingen, at the <a href="https://www.medizin.uni-tuebingen.de/en/Patients/Hospitals/Psychiatry+and+Psychotherapy/General+Psychiatry+and+Psychotherapy/Research/Psychophysiology+_+Optical+Imaging.html" target="_blank" rel="external">Psychophysiology &amp; Optical Imaging research group</a> led by Dr. Ann-Christine Ehlis. The group is located in the Universitätsklinikum Tübingen for Psychiatry and Psychotherapy. It’s a much larger group than the one I’m part of at the Vrije Universiteit, but the topics researched here seem more cohesive. The group mainly focuses on neuro-imaging and other physiological measurements among patients with mental disorders, as well as among healthy (mostly student) volunteers. In the coming months, I’ll be setting up and running a hyperscanning study using near-infrared spectroscopy among close friends/dyads during a social sharing task. I just recently received keys and an employee card from the University and was assigned a room to work in today. So I’m still at the start of the project, but my impressions are very positive, and I’m getting more and more excited about learning some new techniques and skills at this lab group. Plus, Tübingen isn’t a bad looking place to work for a couple months. Not bad at all…</p>
<div class="thumbs"><br><a href="/posts/2016/10/06/setting-up-a-hyperscanning-project-using-nirs-in-tubingen-germany/view_of_tuebingen.JPG" title="A great view of Tuebingen on route to the clinic"><img src="/posts/2016/10/06/setting-up-a-hyperscanning-project-using-nirs-in-tubingen-germany/view_of_tuebingen.JPG"></a><br></div>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>It’s already been a week since I’ve started working at the University of Tübingen, at the <a href="https://www.medizin.uni-tuebingen.de/e]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Dutch Data Prize 2016]]></title>
    <link href="http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2016/08/05/dutch-data-prize-2016/"/>
    <id>http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2016/08/05/dutch-data-prize-2016/</id>
    <published>2016-08-05T09:57:32.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-09-23T12:44:50.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last week, I received word that the <a href="https://touchingresearch.com/posts/2016/04/22/published-data-paper-on-touch-and-the-ern-in-data-in-brief/">EEG data</a> that I had made openly available has been entered for the <a href="http://www.researchdata.nl/en/services/data-prize/" target="_blank" rel="external">Dutch Data Prize 2016</a> by the editor of Data in Brief. According to their website, the Dutch Data Prize is awarded to researchers who make an extra effort to document their data and make it available to others. Sounds like a really cool initiative! I was very (pleasantly) surprised (and a bit proud) to learn that my dataset may have been of value to other people:</p>
<p><em>It’s one of the most highly downloaded datasets from those published in the Data in Brief journal. On average it’s downloaded over 50 times/month from ScienceDirect only, indicating that it’s very valuable to the research community. Next to it, this is a very special dataset which showcases a novel solution of knowledge dissemination and data documentation, making it easy to discover, access and reuse. This solution combines: (1) 171 data files deposited in a trustworthy digital repository (DANS); (2) the description of this dataset published in the open access data journal Data in Brief explaining how the data was acquired; and (3) the full length research article published in the journal Neuroscience Letters presenting the actual results of the data analysis and main outcomes of this study.<br>The data files and the data descriptor are publicly available, under CC-0 and CC-BY licenses respectively. The data files were curated by the DANS data curators and the data article was peer-reviewed by the domain experts. The combination of peer review and data curation provides a double quality stamp and ensures that the data is well documented, collected in accordance with the state of the art methods and protocols and that data has potential for reuse.</em></p>
<p>I know there will be some very strong entries, so I don’t expect a nomination. But, finding out about the potential value of my research data really cemented my desire to make all my data, and if possible all my papers, available Open Access. For those interested, the award ceremony is held November 9th at NWO in The Hague. The Dutch Data Prize 2016 consists of a sculpture and 5k to be spent on making data accessible.  </p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>Last week, I received word that the <a href="https://touchingresearch.com/posts/2016/04/22/published-data-paper-on-touch-and-the-ern-in-d]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Received NWO Open Access grant (for publication of data paper on touch and the ERN)]]></title>
    <link href="http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2016/06/16/received-nwo-open-access-grant-for-publication-of-data-paper-on-touch-and-the-ern/"/>
    <id>http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2016/06/16/received-nwo-open-access-grant-for-publication-of-data-paper-on-touch-and-the-ern/</id>
    <published>2016-06-16T16:31:20.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-06-16T16:32:15.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Earlier this month, I received an Open Access grant from <a href="http://www.nwo.nl/en" target="_blank" rel="external">NWO</a> (Netherlands Organization for Scientific Research) to cover the publication costs for <a href="https://touchingresearch.com/posts/2016/04/22/published-data-paper-on-touch-and-the-ern-in-data-in-brief/">“Data on simulated interpersonal touch, individual differences and the error-related negativity” in the journal Data in Brief</a>.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>Earlier this month, I received an Open Access grant from <a href="http://www.nwo.nl/en" target="_blank" rel="external">NWO</a> (Netherlan]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Some introductions to R Statistics]]></title>
    <link href="http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2016/06/06/some-introductions-to-r-statistics/"/>
    <id>http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2016/06/06/some-introductions-to-r-statistics/</id>
    <published>2016-06-06T18:16:05.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-06-10T18:29:04.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve recently started learning R again, picking up where I left off last year. It’s an introductory course (three afternoons) for PhD students and other faculty, organized through the Kurt Lewin Institute. Here are a few online resources that I found especially helpful and accessible for a beginner. These are free, friendly, online self-paced introductory courses on using R/RStudio. I did them about half a year ago in my spare time/weekends and really enjoyed myself.<br><a href="http://tryr.codeschool.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">Try R by Codeschool</a><br><a href="https://www.datacamp.com/introduction-to-statistics" target="_blank" rel="external">Introduction to statistics by Datacamp</a><br><a href="https://www.edx.org/course/introduction-r-data-science-microsoft-dat204x-0" target="_blank" rel="external">Introduction to R data science by edX</a></p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>I’ve recently started learning R again, picking up where I left off last year. It’s an introductory course (three afternoons) for PhD stu]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Attended UBVU seminar: Publishing and integrity: is openness the answer?]]></title>
    <link href="http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2016/06/04/attended-ubvu-seminar-publishing-and-integrity-is-openness-the-answer/"/>
    <id>http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2016/06/04/attended-ubvu-seminar-publishing-and-integrity-is-openness-the-answer/</id>
    <published>2016-06-04T16:37:28.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-06-04T16:47:45.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I wrote a post about the <a href="https://touchingresearch.com/posts/2015/12/09/participated-in-phd-course-on-scientific-integrity/">Scientific Integrity PhD course of the VU medical center</a> last December. Related to that course, I recently received an e-mail about the <a href="https://www.nrin.nl/" target="_blank" rel="external">first conference of the Netherlands Research Integrity Network</a>, which is held in Amsterdam. I signed up for it, but may not be able to attend it. Nonetheless, while browsing through their website, I noticed that the VU University Library was organizing a very interesting seminar on publishing and integrity, and more specifically about whether openness and transparancy can decrease research misconduct (such as the use of <a href="https://replicationindex.wordpress.com/2015/01/24/questionable-research-practices-definition-detect-and-recommendations-for-better-practices/" target="_blank" rel="external">Questionable Research Practices</a>) and increase the quality of scientific publications (through Open Access policies) and open peer review. Follow <a href="http://www.vu.nl/nl/nieuws-agenda/agenda/2016/apr-jun/2016-05-24-publishing-and-integrity.aspx" target="_blank" rel="external">this link</a> to see an overview of the topics and speakers.</p>
<p>Questionable research practices, the importance of preregistration, and the flaws of the peer review system were already familiar topics to me. However, the talk on Open Access publishing provided some very interesting information and helped me understand my own discomfort in paying to openly publish my research. Apparently, charging huge fees for Open Access publishing can be an extremely lucrative business model. There are many online articles on the issues surrounding such business models and their effects on the scientific literature. For example, you can start reading <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2016/01/06/plos-one-shrinks-by-11-percent/" target="_blank" rel="external">here</a>, <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2010/10/12/cascading-peer-review-future-of-open-access/" target="_blank" rel="external">here</a>, or <a href="http://www.nrc.nl/handelsblad/2015/01/10/de-chaos-van-open-access-1454804" target="_blank" rel="external">here (Dutch article)</a>.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>I wrote a post about the <a href="https://touchingresearch.com/posts/2015/12/09/participated-in-phd-course-on-scientific-integrity/">Scie]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Published data paper on touch and the ERN in Data in Brief]]></title>
    <link href="http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2016/04/22/published-data-paper-on-touch-and-the-ern-in-data-in-brief/"/>
    <id>http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2016/04/22/published-data-paper-on-touch-and-the-ern-in-data-in-brief/</id>
    <published>2016-04-22T08:27:17.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-04-25T08:37:02.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The final version of our data paper titled “Data on simulated interpersonal touch, individual differences and the error-related negativity” has been published in Data in Brief, an Open Access journal. The full reference is: Tjew-A-Sin, M., Tops, M., Heslenfeld, D.J., &amp; Koole, S.L. (2016). Data on simulated interpersonal touch, individual differences and the error-related negativity. Data in Brief, 7, 1327–1330. <a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S235234091630230X" target="_blank" rel="external">Click here to check it out.</a></p>
<p>Abstract: The dataset includes data from the electroencephalogram study reported in our paper: ‘Effects of simulated interpersonal touch and trait intrinsic motivation on the error-related negativity’ (doi:10.1016/j.neulet.2016.01.044) (Tjew-A-Sin et al., 2016) [1]. The data was collected at the psychology laboratories at the Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam in 2012 among a Dutch-speaking student sample. The dataset consists of the measures described in the paper, as well as additional (exploratory) measures including the Five-Factor Personality Inventory, the Connectedness to Nature Scale, the Rosenberg Self-esteem Scale and a scale measuring life stress. The data can be used for replication purposes, meta-analyses, and exploratory analyses, as well as cross-cultural comparisons of touch and/or ERN effects. The authors also welcome collaborative research based on re-analyses of the data. The data described is available at a data repository called the DANS archive: <a href="http://persistent-identifier.nl/?identifier=urn:nbn:nl:ui:13-tzbk-gg" target="_blank" rel="external">http://persistent-identifier.nl/?identifier=urn:nbn:nl:ui:13-tzbk-gg</a>.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>The final version of our data paper titled “Data on simulated interpersonal touch, individual differences and the error-related negativit]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Published research paper on touch and the ERN in Neuroscience Letters]]></title>
    <link href="http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2016/04/08/published-research-paper-on-touch-and-the-ern-in-neuroscience-letters/"/>
    <id>http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2016/04/08/published-research-paper-on-touch-and-the-ern-in-neuroscience-letters/</id>
    <published>2016-04-08T07:45:21.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-04-08T07:50:16.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Our paper titled “Effects of simulated interpersonal touch and trait intrinsic motivation on the error-related negativity” has been published in Neuroscience Letters. It’s Open Access, so feel free to <a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S030439401630043X" target="_blank" rel="external">look it up</a>. The full (APA) reference is: Tjew-A-Sin, M., Tops, M., Heslenfeld, D.J., &amp; Koole, S.L. (2016). Effects of simulated interpersonal touch and trait intrinsic motivation on the error-related negativity. Neuroscience Letters, 617, 134-138.</p>
<p>Abstract: The error-related negativity (ERN or Ne) is a negative event-related brain potential that peaks about 20–100 ms after people perform an incorrect response in choice reaction time tasks. Prior research has shown that the ERN may be enhanced by situational and dispositional factors that promote intrinsic motivation. Building on and extending this work the authors hypothesized that simulated interpersonal touch may increase task engagement and thereby increase ERN amplitude. To test this notion, 20 participants performed a Go/No-Go task while holding a teddy bear or a same-sized cardboard box. As expected, the ERN was significantly larger when participants held a teddy bear rather than a cardboard box. This effect was most pronounced for people high (rather than low) in trait intrinsic motivation, who may depend more on intrinsically motivating task cues to maintain task engagement. These findings highlight the potential benefits of simulated interpersonal touch in stimulating attention to errors, especially among people who are intrinsically motivated.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>Our paper titled “Effects of simulated interpersonal touch and trait intrinsic motivation on the error-related negativity” has been publi]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Attended Master thesis defense: Designing a mediated touch interaction for increased empathy between alexithymics and their loved ones]]></title>
    <link href="http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2016/03/31/attended-master-thesis-defense-designing-a-mediated-touch-interaction-for-increased-empathy-between-alexithymics-and-their-loved-ones/"/>
    <id>http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2016/03/31/attended-master-thesis-defense-designing-a-mediated-touch-interaction-for-increased-empathy-between-alexithymics-and-their-loved-ones/</id>
    <published>2016-03-31T14:58:53.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-07-15T18:18:35.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently attended the Master defense of Viola Tjew-A-Sin (my sister), who graduated with top marks from the two-year Design for Interaction Master at TU Delft. Her project was about the design of a mediated (warm) touch interaction that could increase empathy or restore a sense of connection between people with alexithymia, who struggle to recognize and express emotions, and their romantic partners. Check out the project idea and summary <a href="/posts/2016/03/31/attended-master-thesis-defense-designing-a-mediated-touch-interaction-for-increased-empathy-between-alexithymics-and-their-loved-ones/project_summary.pdf" title="Executive summary by Viola Tjew-A-Sin">here</a>, and her design portfolio at <a href="http://violatjew.nl" target="_blank" rel="external">violatjew.nl</a>. </p>
<div class="thumbs"><br><a href="/posts/2016/03/31/attended-master-thesis-defense-designing-a-mediated-touch-interaction-for-increased-empathy-between-alexithymics-and-their-loved-ones/mediated_touch_design.jpg" title="Prototype mediated touch interaction"><img src="/posts/2016/03/31/attended-master-thesis-defense-designing-a-mediated-touch-interaction-for-increased-empathy-between-alexithymics-and-their-loved-ones/mediated_touch_design.jpg"></a><br></div>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>I recently attended the Master defense of Viola Tjew-A-Sin (my sister), who graduated with top marks from the two-year Design for Interac]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Participated in Postdoc Career Development Initiative course]]></title>
    <link href="http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2015/12/20/participated-in-postdoc-career-development-course/"/>
    <id>http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2015/12/20/participated-in-postdoc-career-development-course/</id>
    <published>2015-12-20T14:44:40.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-07-08T14:55:22.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently finished a very good 3-day course organized by <a href="http://www.pcdi.nl" target="_blank" rel="external">PCDI</a> called Employability Outside Academia. It’s a course for Postdocs and PhDs that is given in small groups and led by an experienced coach. Although it is focused on helping early career researchers make the transition out of academia (and into industry for example), the course is also for researchers who want to figure out whether they want to stay. During the course, there is a lot of focus on personal interests, competencies, skill gaps, talents and ambitions. There are plenty of practical exercises and resources that help you discover them. At the end of the course you end up with about 60 pages of personal insights to help you design your career to your liking and lots to think about. I highly recommend the course, especially if you started your PhD at a young age/fresh out of university.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>I recently finished a very good 3-day course organized by <a href="http://www.pcdi.nl" target="_blank" rel="external">PCDI</a> called Emp]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Participated in PhD course on Scientific Integrity]]></title>
    <link href="http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2015/12/09/participated-in-phd-course-on-scientific-integrity/"/>
    <id>http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2015/12/09/participated-in-phd-course-on-scientific-integrity/</id>
    <published>2015-12-09T18:38:26.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-05-22T18:29:45.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I participated in a two-day ‘blended’ (online plus class module) course on <a href="https://www.vumc.com/branch/phd/EducationPhD/EducationPhDgeneral/IntegrityEthicsDevelopment/" target="_blank" rel="external">Scientific Integrity</a> at the VU Medical Center. The course is part of their PhD Training and Education program, and was mostly attended by PhD students in the medical field. It was interesting to learn about the issues that they struggle with in their research, especially since their choices may have severe health implications for a great number of people. At one of the class meetings, the lecturer asked us to name the biggest case of scientific fraud in the Netherlands. The answer was overwhelmingly in favor of the social psychologist Diederik Stapel, whose misconduct was covered extensively by Dutch news agencies. In contrast, very few had even heard of the option the lecturer introduced: <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Don_Poldermans" target="_blank" rel="external">Don Poldermans</a>, a former cardiovascular medicine researcher (and head of his unit) whose fabricated data was used in 2009 to (mis)inform European hospital guidelines, which were not corrected until August 2014. It is very likely that his data fabrication has led to many unnecessary patient deaths. Although the online module, which was focused on an US audience, was less relevant to the Dutch context, I greatly appreciated the personal touch in the subgroup sessions, in which we openly and extensively discussed the ethical dilemmas in our own work and dissected them as a group: what would you do and why?</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>I participated in a two-day ‘blended’ (online plus class module) course on <a href="https://www.vumc.com/branch/phd/EducationPhD/Educatio]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Gave a guest lecture on social emotion regulation]]></title>
    <link href="http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2015/11/19/gave-a-guest-lecture-on-social-emotion-regulation/"/>
    <id>http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2015/11/19/gave-a-guest-lecture-on-social-emotion-regulation/</id>
    <published>2015-11-19T15:31:52.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-04-01T14:45:26.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I gave a guest lecture/workshop for the research master course <a href="http://www.vu.nl/nl/studiegids/2015-2016/master/c-d/clinical-developmental-psychopathology/index.aspx?view=module&amp;origin=50961128x50766690&amp;id=51100781" target="_blank" rel="external">The Psychology of Emotion Regulation: From Basic Principles to Clinical Applications</a> for first- and second year students of the research master Clinical and Developmental Psychopathology at the Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam.</p>
<p>The workshop was focused on recent findings related to emotional coregulation, stress-buffering effects of social support/frequent hugs, social sharing of emotion, and the role of individual differences such as attachment style in social emotion expression and regulation. A selection of the class material:</p>
<p>Butler, E. A., &amp; Randall, A. K. (2013). Emotional coregulation in close relationships. Emotion Review, 5(2), 202-210.<br>Cohen, S., Janicki-Deverts, D., Turner, R. B., &amp; Doyle, W. J. (2015). Does hugging provide stress-buffering social support? A study of susceptibility to upper respiratory infection and ill-ness. Psychological science, 26(2), 135-147.<br>Rimé, B. (2009). Emotion elicits the social sharing of emotion: Theory and empirical review. Emotion Review, 1(1), 60-85.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>I gave a guest lecture/workshop for the research master course <a href="http://www.vu.nl/nl/studiegids/2015-2016/master/c-d/clinical-deve]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Attended Hack the Body expert meeting on synchrony]]></title>
    <link href="http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2015/09/26/attended-hack-the-body-expert-meeting-on-synchrony/"/>
    <id>http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2015/09/26/attended-hack-the-body-expert-meeting-on-synchrony/</id>
    <published>2015-09-26T20:13:53.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-03-14T20:53:05.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was invited to the <a href="http://www.baltanlaboratories.org/article/event/hack-the-body-during-todaysart" target="_blank" rel="external">Hack the Body expert meeting on synchrony</a>, organized by Baltan Laboratories and Holst Centre. It was part of the <a href="http://todaysart.nl/2015/symposium/hack-the-body/" target="_blank" rel="external">2015 TodaysArt festival</a>, specifically the Bright Collisions Symposium. I prepared a short presentation, but ended up using the material mostly for discussions with the group. The meeting brought together scientists, artists, engineers and product developers to discuss topics related to biometric synchronization: “Can two or more people synchronize their biometric signals (heart beat, respiration, gsr-sweat) with each other? Can synchrony of these signals be induced? What measure of synchrony can be established? How can synchrony be represented, modeled within the environment, and used as a catalyst for feedback? What hardware can we use to measure biometric sensing and feedback such as ECG, EEG, GSR?” </p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>I was invited to the <a href="http://www.baltanlaboratories.org/article/event/hack-the-body-during-todaysart" target="_blank" rel="extern]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Presented at the 1st Dutch Touch meeting]]></title>
    <link href="http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2015/07/03/presented-at-the-1st-dutch-touch-meeting/"/>
    <id>http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2015/07/03/presented-at-the-1st-dutch-touch-meeting/</id>
    <published>2015-07-03T20:13:53.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-03-27T16:16:22.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On the 3rd of July, I participated in the <a href="https://www.3tu.nl/ht/en/news/first-dutch-sat-meeting/" target="_blank" rel="external">1st meeting on the study of social and affective touch in the Netherlands</a>. The main goal of the meeting was to explore possibilities and interests of Dutch scientists, tech people and artists who are involved in this topic to collaborate and regularly come together. We could then share ideas, insights, equipment etc. It was very inspiring to meet people from different disciplines who share a similar interest. For instance, in their art project <a href="http://www.lancelmaat.nl/work/e.e.g-kiss/" target="_blank" rel="external">E.E.G. KISS</a>, artists Karen Lancel and Herman Maat of TU Delft use ultra-portable EEG headsets to measure the brain activity of romantic partners while they are kissing, hugging and touching each other. I presented some of my recent findings on the soothing effects of soft materials, especially for insecurely attached individuals. My sister (and soon-to-be industrial engineer specialized in Design for Interaction), Viola Tjew-A-Sin, was also invited to the meeting. Her <a href="http://studenten.tudelft.nl/nl/informatie/faculteitspecifiek/industrieel-ontwerpen/agenda/event/detail/graduate-viola-tjew-a-sin-dfi/" target="_blank" rel="external">graduation project is about mediated social touch</a>, specifically the aspect of warmth, and how it may be used to increase empathy and connectedness between people with alexithymia and their loved ones.  </p>
<div class="thumbs"><br><a href="/posts/2015/07/03/presented-at-the-1st-dutch-touch-meeting/dutchtouch1_1.jpg" title="1st Dutch Touch location"><img src="/posts/2015/07/03/presented-at-the-1st-dutch-touch-meeting/dutchtouch1_1.jpg"></a><br><a href="/posts/2015/07/03/presented-at-the-1st-dutch-touch-meeting/dutchtouch1_2.jpg" title="1st Dutch Touch group"><img src="/posts/2015/07/03/presented-at-the-1st-dutch-touch-meeting/dutchtouch1_2.jpg"></a><br></div>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>On the 3rd of July, I participated in the <a href="https://www.3tu.nl/ht/en/news/first-dutch-sat-meeting/" target="_blank" rel="external"]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Presented at NIAS-Lorentz workshop on social support and technology]]></title>
    <link href="http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2015/03/21/presented-at-nias-lorentz-workshop-on-social-support-and-technology/"/>
    <id>http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2015/03/21/presented-at-nias-lorentz-workshop-on-social-support-and-technology/</id>
    <published>2015-03-21T12:00:33.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-02-21T14:23:24.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The past week, I had the pleasure of taking part in a one-week <a href="https://www.lorentzcenter.nl/lc/web/2015/688/info.php3?wsid=688" target="_blank" rel="external">NIAS-Lorentz workshop on “Social support TAT: Theory, Applications, and Technology”</a> that aimed to bring together different (e.g., biological, clinical, neurological and psychological perspectives) on social support. The workshop also mixed scientific talks with hardware and software development by inviting people from both the scientific and the tech community. I very much enjoyed both elements of the workshop. Based on my poster abstract, I was invited to give a one hour talk on my research on touch and existential concerns, for which I also received a Best Paper award (also on behalf of my co-authors). For my presentation, I worked in findings from my newer line of research on loneliness and mental health (see abstract below). All in all, it’s been a very interesting and exciting week.</p>
<p>“Loneliness Moderates the Association Between Vulnerable Personality and Mental Health</p>
<p>A number of personality traits – such as low self-esteem, high neuroticism, high thought suppression, and high alexithymia- appear to reflect latent vulnerabilities, in that these traits are consistently predictive of poor mental health. However, not all people with vulnerable personality traits display poor mental health, suggesting that there might be moderating variables that determine whether these people’s latent vulnerability becomes translated into overt psychological complaints. In our research, we examined whether loneliness is one such moderating variable. Because people have an innate need for social connections with others, we suggest that loneliness is a critical circumstance that leads to deteriorations in mental health among people with vulnerable personality traits. I will present five studies, including three cross-sectional studies, one longitudinal study, and one experimental study, that support this line of reasoning. Taken together, these findings suggest that loneliness is a catalyst for the development of mental health problems among people with latent vulnerabilities in their personality functioning.”  </p>
<div class="thumbs"><br><a href="/posts/2015/03/21/presented-at-nias-lorentz-workshop-on-social-support-and-technology/social_support_tat.png" title="Workshop poster"><img src="/posts/2015/03/21/presented-at-nias-lorentz-workshop-on-social-support-and-technology/social_support_tat.png"></a><br><a href="/posts/2015/03/21/presented-at-nias-lorentz-workshop-on-social-support-and-technology/tech_at_workshop.jpg" title="Tech at the workshop"><img src="/posts/2015/03/21/presented-at-nias-lorentz-workshop-on-social-support-and-technology/tech_at_workshop.jpg"></a><br></div>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>The past week, I had the pleasure of taking part in a one-week <a href="https://www.lorentzcenter.nl/lc/web/2015/688/info.php3?wsid=688" ]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Presented poster at the 2015 ICPS conference]]></title>
    <link href="http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2015/03/15/presented-poster-at-the-2015-icps-conference/"/>
    <id>http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2015/03/15/presented-poster-at-the-2015-icps-conference/</id>
    <published>2015-03-15T21:13:53.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-02-13T12:42:40.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just recently attended the very first International Convention of Psychological Science (ICPS) in Amsterdam. It was a very nice, open and inclusive conference. I presented a new poster on how loneliness moderates the association between different vulnerability factors and mental health problems. This poster shows just some of my findings, but gives an idea of the broad scope of the effect.</p>
<div class="thumbs"><br><a href="/posts/2015/03/15/presented-poster-at-the-2015-icps-conference/ICPS_poster1.JPG" title="ICPS poster"><img src="/posts/2015/03/15/presented-poster-at-the-2015-icps-conference/ICPS_poster1.JPG"></a><br><a href="/posts/2015/03/15/presented-poster-at-the-2015-icps-conference/ICPS_poster2.JPG" title="ICPS poster close-up"><img src="/posts/2015/03/15/presented-poster-at-the-2015-icps-conference/ICPS_poster2.JPG"></a><br></div>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>I just recently attended the very first International Convention of Psychological Science (ICPS) in Amsterdam. It was a very nice, open a]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Presented at the 2014 EASP Conference]]></title>
    <link href="http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2014/07/20/presented-at-the-2014-easp-conference/"/>
    <id>http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2014/07/20/presented-at-the-2014-easp-conference/</id>
    <published>2014-07-20T15:03:08.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-02-06T19:35:36.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I gave a talk at the EASP conference in Amsterdam on my embodied Terror Management research. It was part of the symposium: ‘What would you do under threat? Current and future directions in Terror Management Theory’. This was my first time presenting for an international audience at a big social psychology conference. It went very smoothly. I really enjoyed it, especially talking to people afterwards. You could tell that the people who showed up were really interested in either touch and/or research on existential psychology. I really liked the conference in general. It was very open and inclusive to everyone. I met some very nice people, enjoyed exploring Amsterdam and got to try out the Google Glass.</p>
<div class="thumbs"><br><a href="/posts/2014/07/20/presented-at-the-2014-easp-conference/EASP1.jpg" title="EASP conference"><img src="/posts/2014/07/20/presented-at-the-2014-easp-conference/EASP1.jpg"></a><br><a href="/posts/2014/07/20/presented-at-the-2014-easp-conference/EASP2.jpg" title="EASP Amsterdam"><img src="/posts/2014/07/20/presented-at-the-2014-easp-conference/EASP2.jpg"></a><br><a href="/posts/2014/07/20/presented-at-the-2014-easp-conference/EASP3.jpg" title="EASP Google Glass"><img src="/posts/2014/07/20/presented-at-the-2014-easp-conference/EASP3.jpg"></a><br></div>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>I gave a talk at the EASP conference in Amsterdam on my embodied Terror Management research. It was part of the symposium: ‘What would yo]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Presented at 2014 KLI Conference]]></title>
    <link href="http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2014/05/24/presented-at-2014-kli-conference/"/>
    <id>http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2014/05/24/presented-at-2014-kli-conference/</id>
    <published>2014-05-24T12:37:16.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-02-26T14:02:53.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I presented my research on embodied terror management at the 2014 Kurt Lewin Institute Conference. This biennial conference is held at a large conference center in Zeist, surrounded by nature. On the morning of the second day, I got up early and enjoyed a very pleasant walk in the woods before joining the sessions again. To celebrate the 20th anniversary of the institute, everyone received a book showing the history and achievements of the institute and short interviews with all KLI alumni. It’s very interesting to read about the career paths that people took after getting their PhD.</p>
<div class="thumbs"><br><a href="/posts/2014/05/24/presented-at-2014-kli-conference/20th_KLI.jpg" title="KLI alumni showcase"><img src="/posts/2014/05/24/presented-at-2014-kli-conference/20th_KLI.jpg"></a><br></div>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>I presented my research on embodied terror management at the 2014 Kurt Lewin Institute Conference. This biennial conference is held at a ]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Published embodied terror management paper]]></title>
    <link href="http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2014/02/04/published-embodied-terror-management-paper/"/>
    <id>http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2014/02/04/published-embodied-terror-management-paper/</id>
    <published>2014-02-04T21:13:53.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-12-12T21:02:31.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Our paper titled “Embodied terror management: (Simulated) Interpersonal touch alleviates existential concerns among individuals with low self-esteem” was recently <a href="http://pss.sagepub.com/content/25/1/30" target="_blank" rel="external">published in Psychological Science</a>. It is based on some of the research on interpersonal touch that I did during my year-long internship at the VU University together with Sander Koole. I am very pleased that it made it into the world so soon. The research has been covered by a number of websites, some more accurate than others:</p>
<ul>
<li>The <a href="http://www.psychologicalscience.org/index.php/news/releases/touch-may-alleviate-existential-fears-for-people-with-low-self-esteem.html" target="_blank" rel="external">news item from the journal</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/femail/article-2509343/Cuddling-teddy-bear-ease-existential-angst-cure-fear-dying-says-new-study.html" target="_blank" rel="external">The Daily Mail</a></li>
<li>A brief mention in <a href="http://dewerelddraaitdoor.vara.nl/media/304354" target="_blank" rel="external">De Wereld Draait Door (in Dutch)</a></li>
<li>An <a href="http://www.beblissed.nl/stress-angst-of-werkloos-knuffel-een-teddybeer-knuffeltherapie/" target="_blank" rel="external">interview with Sander (in Dutch)</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>Our paper titled “Embodied terror management: (Simulated) Interpersonal touch alleviates existential concerns among individuals with low ]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Presented at 2013 ASPO conference]]></title>
    <link href="http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2013/12/15/presented-at-2013-aspo-conference/"/>
    <id>http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2013/12/15/presented-at-2013-aspo-conference/</id>
    <published>2013-12-15T21:13:53.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-03-04T20:01:10.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I presented my touch research at the <a href="http://www.sociale-psychologie.nl/" target="_blank" rel="external">Dutch ASPO conference for social psychologists</a>. This was the last year that a short peer-reviewed Dutch version of your article would be published in the conference book and the last time the conference was held completely in Dutch. It was a fun process to summarize my touch results in Dutch. I’m happy to have been part of these traditions, especially because it was for the last time.</p>
<div class="thumbs"><br><a href="/posts/2013/12/15/presented-at-2013-aspo-conference/ASPO_book.jpg" title="ASPO 2013 Conference Book"><img src="/posts/2013/12/15/presented-at-2013-aspo-conference/ASPO_book.jpg"></a><br><a href="/posts/2013/12/15/presented-at-2013-aspo-conference/ASPO_article.jpg" title="My ASPO article"><img src="/posts/2013/12/15/presented-at-2013-aspo-conference/ASPO_article.jpg"></a><br></div>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>I presented my touch research at the <a href="http://www.sociale-psychologie.nl/" target="_blank" rel="external">Dutch ASPO conference fo]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Attended interdisciplinary summer school on embodied intersubjectivity]]></title>
    <link href="http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2013/06/16/attended-interdisciplinary-summer-school-on-embodied-intersubjectivity/"/>
    <id>http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2013/06/16/attended-interdisciplinary-summer-school-on-embodied-intersubjectivity/</id>
    <published>2013-06-16T20:10:16.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-12-25T14:55:00.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was selected (on a competitive basis) to participate in a very interesting, interdisciplinary summer school on the island of Aegina, Greece, on embodied intersubjectivity. They invited around 50 PhD students, post-docs, and other (mostly) young researchers and of course a large number of people to teach us. The presentations were given by leading researchers from the fields of experimental,developmental and social psychology, cognitive and social neuroscience, anthropology, primatology and philosophy. The programme included sessions on:</p>
<ul>
<li>1st person perspectives of embodiment</li>
<li>The embodied self in interaction with the world</li>
<li>Ontogenetic and phylogenetic perspectives on social cognition</li>
<li>Transition from 3rd person- to 2nd person perspective in social neuroscience</li>
<li>Embodying other people’s minds and bodies</li>
</ul>
<p>It was a very nice week with many interesting lectures, kind people, a beautiful location and great food. During the week, I also gave a short presentation on my work on touch and existential concerns, and I presented a poster afterwards on the same topic. Before I left Greece, I was able to sneak a very nice visit to the Acropolis and the Acropolis Museum.</p>
<div class="thumbs"><br><a href="/posts/2013/06/16/attended-interdisciplinary-summer-school-on-embodied-intersubjectivity/aegina_poster.jpg" title="Poster session at Aegina summer school"><img src="/posts/2013/06/16/attended-interdisciplinary-summer-school-on-embodied-intersubjectivity/aegina_poster.jpg"></a><br><a href="/posts/2013/06/16/attended-interdisciplinary-summer-school-on-embodied-intersubjectivity/aegina_location.jpg" title="Aegina summer school view"><img src="/posts/2013/06/16/attended-interdisciplinary-summer-school-on-embodied-intersubjectivity/aegina_location.jpg"></a><br></div>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>I was selected (on a competitive basis) to participate in a very interesting, interdisciplinary summer school on the island of Aegina, Gr]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Presented research at 2013 APS and SSM conference]]></title>
    <link href="http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2013/05/30/presented-research-at-2013-aps-and-ssm-conference/"/>
    <id>http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2013/05/30/presented-research-at-2013-aps-and-ssm-conference/</id>
    <published>2013-05-30T16:40:58.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-01-31T17:57:22.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I visited my first large international psychology conferences: the 2013 APS conference in Washington and also the preconference by the Society for the Study of Motivation (SSM). Sander presented our findings on touch during the symposium: “Embodying motivation: How bodily experiences shape our goals and desires”, which he co-chaired. At the APS conference, I presented a poster on the same research. It was a very exciting few days and I must have seen at least 40 presentations on so many different topics. I loved the wide variety of research fields and topics. I definitely would like to visit another APS conference in the future, and to present some research myself.</p>
<div class="thumbs"><br><a href="/posts/2013/05/30/presented-research-at-2013-aps-and-ssm-conference/APS_poster.jpg" title="APS conference poster"><img src="/posts/2013/05/30/presented-research-at-2013-aps-and-ssm-conference/APS_poster.jpg"></a><br></div>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>I visited my first large international psychology conferences: the 2013 APS conference in Washington and also the preconference by the So]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Published interpersonal touch article at In-Mind.org]]></title>
    <link href="http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2013/02/16/published-interpersonal-touch-article-at-in-mind-org/"/>
    <id>http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2013/02/16/published-interpersonal-touch-article-at-in-mind-org/</id>
    <published>2013-02-16T21:16:32.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-01-22T21:19:04.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sander and I wrote a <a href="http://www.in-mind.org/article/that-human-touch-that-means-so-much-exploring-the-tactile-dimension-of-social-life" target="_blank" rel="external">review article</a> for the Inquisitive Mind (or In-Mind; see <a href="http://www.in-mind.org" target="_blank" rel="external">In-Mind.org</a>) on the effects of interpersonal touch. This on-line peer-reviewed magazine aims to make social-psychological research available to a broad audience by providing articles that are highly entertaining, educating and accessible. This was my first time working on an article that had to be accessible to a broach audience. We had to revise it quite a few times, but it was an exciting challenge. The title and intro of the paper are shown below:</p>
<p>“That human touch that means so much: Exploring the tactile dimension of social life</p>
<p>Interpersonal touch is a fundamental but undervalued aspect of human nature. In the present article, the authors review psychological research showing that even fleeting forms of touch may have a powerful impact on our emotional and social functioning. Given its significant beneficial effects, touch may be valuable as a therapeutic or health-promoting tool.”</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>Sander and I wrote a <a href="http://www.in-mind.org/article/that-human-touch-that-means-so-much-exploring-the-tactile-dimension-of-socia]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Attended Heidelberg conference on embodiment]]></title>
    <link href="http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2012/10/03/attended-heidelberg-conference-on-embodiment/"/>
    <id>http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2012/10/03/attended-heidelberg-conference-on-embodiment/</id>
    <published>2012-10-03T13:57:50.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-01-17T15:48:53.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We attended a conference on ‘The implications of embodiment: enactive, clinical, social’ as a lab group. This is my first week as a PhD Student, and my first meeting with the other lab members, so this is quite the start! The lab group will mainly research embodied emotion regulation, and is funded by an ERC grant that was awarded to Sander Koole last year. We will be working at the Clinical Psychology department at the VU. The conference was very interesting and unique with more exploratory as well as very experimental and data-heavy talks. I liked how casual the conference was, with informal dress code, lots of students and a surprising focus on meditation and dance. Sander gave a short but sweet presentation about our research on touch and existential concerns.</p>
<div class="thumbs"><br><a href="/posts/2012/10/03/attended-heidelberg-conference-on-embodiment/heidelberg_conf.jpg" title="Heidelberg conference on embodiment"><img src="/posts/2012/10/03/attended-heidelberg-conference-on-embodiment/heidelberg_conf.jpg"></a><br></div>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>We attended a conference on ‘The implications of embodiment: enactive, clinical, social’ as a lab group. This is my first week as a PhD S]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Received NWO Mosaic grant to do PhD research]]></title>
    <link href="http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2012/09/15/received-nwo-mosaic-grant-to-do-phd-research/"/>
    <id>http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2012/09/15/received-nwo-mosaic-grant-to-do-phd-research/</id>
    <published>2012-09-15T20:29:19.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-01-17T15:20:59.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After a huge effort from Sander Koole (my internship supervisor) and I in the past half year or so, I recently <a href="http://www.nwo.nl/actueel/nieuws/2012/Moza%C3%AFek-toekenningen+bij+MaGW.html" target="_blank" rel="external">received the Mosaic grant</a> from the NWO (Netherlands Organization for Scientific Research). In January this year, I found out through a fellow student that I was eligible for this grant, but we only had a few weeks until the application deadline which included a detailed grant proposal. We had to work hard and fast to make the deadline. After making the first selection phase (41 out of 210) in February, I followed workshops to further develop my research ideas and to prepare a presentation to convince a multidisciplinary committee of professors to fund the project.</p>
<p>This summer, during my vacation, I was informed that I was one of 20 to receive the grant. Not long after, near the end of the year, NWO also held a short ceremony to award the grants in person. This was also the last time that the grant was awarded because of budget cuts, which does make it extra special. Even without applying for this grant, the last year at the VU has been a huge learning experience for me, and also very challenging, but I am very grateful that these efforts have been rewarded. It is the cherry on the cake. This is a short summary of the research project:</p>
<p>“The proposed research investigates how and why affirming feelings of belonging may improve academic achievement among ethnic minority students. The resulting insights will be used to design powerful new belongingness interventions. These interventions will be evaluated in terms of their effectiveness in closing the minority achievement gap.”</p>
<div class="thumbs"><br><a href="/posts/2012/09/15/received-nwo-mosaic-grant-to-do-phd-research/mosaic_award.jpg" title="Award ceremony NWO Mosaic grant"><img src="/posts/2012/09/15/received-nwo-mosaic-grant-to-do-phd-research/mosaic_award.jpg"></a><br></div>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>After a huge effort from Sander Koole (my internship supervisor) and I in the past half year or so, I recently <a href="http://www.nwo.nl]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Conducting the touch ERP study]]></title>
    <link href="http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2012/05/10/conducting-the-touch-erp-study/"/>
    <id>http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2012/05/10/conducting-the-touch-erp-study/</id>
    <published>2012-05-10T17:42:09.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-01-11T18:42:58.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have been testing participants for an EEG study on the effects of simulated interpersonal touch on a neural marker of error processing: the error-related negativity. I am slowly getting a knack for preparing participants for each recording. I learned of all the possible ways an EEG recording may be distorted, and the care that goes into obtaining clean interpretable data. Also, many technical problems needed to be solved and it was a challenge to deal with them and to liaise with the technical staff about these matters. Dr Koole found two psychology graduates who assisted me with the data collection. It was fun to instruct them all that I had learned during the past weeks.</p>
<p>After testing the last participants the previous week, two researchers from another research group started using the laboratory and equipment. Because they had no previous experience with EEG research, I was asked to instruct them on the workings of the lab and how to prepare participants. Again, it was nice to transfer the skills and knowledge I had learned to other people new to the technique. Soon after, I followed a brief one-day tutorial given by Dr Heslenfeld on how to analyze the EEG data using Neuroscan. </p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>I have been testing participants for an EEG study on the effects of simulated interpersonal touch on a neural marker of error processing:]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Internship research mentioned in Intermediair Magazine]]></title>
    <link href="http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2012/01/04/internship-research-mentioned-in-intermediair-magazine/"/>
    <id>http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2012/01/04/internship-research-mentioned-in-intermediair-magazine/</id>
    <published>2012-01-04T21:13:53.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-12-21T20:11:05.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The research that I’m working on with Sander Koole at the VU University has found its way into the Dutch magazine Intermediair. It is an issue on ‘troost’, which is Dutch for ‘comfort’. In our research we find that interpersonal touch, but also touching soft stuffed animals, can be very comforting for people with low self-esteem.</p>
<div class="thumbs"><br><a href="/posts/2012/01/04/internship-research-mentioned-in-intermediair-magazine/intermediair.jpg" title="Intermediair"><img src="/posts/2012/01/04/internship-research-mentioned-in-intermediair-magazine/intermediair.jpg"></a><br></div>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>The research that I’m working on with Sander Koole at the VU University has found its way into the Dutch magazine Intermediair. It is an ]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Attended international expert meeting on meaning]]></title>
    <link href="http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2011/12/02/attended-international-expert-meeting-on-meaning/"/>
    <id>http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2011/12/02/attended-international-expert-meeting-on-meaning/</id>
    <published>2011-12-02T15:22:23.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-12-31T15:27:34.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In November, I took part in a two-day international expert meeting in Tilburg on the psychological significance of meaning and other existential research topics. Dr Koole presented some of my findings on touch and existential concerns. This was a significant learning experience, and a very inspiring event to have been a part of. I came to know about so many lines of interesting research and so many new ideas. It cemented my desire to become a psychological researcher.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>In November, I took part in a two-day international expert meeting in Tilburg on the psychological significance of meaning and other exis]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>