<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  
  <title><![CDATA[Touching Research]]></title>
  <subtitle><![CDATA[Experimental Psychology]]></subtitle>
  <link href="//atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://touchingresearch.com//"/>
  <updated>2015-12-12T21:02:31.000Z</updated>
  <id>http://touchingresearch.com//</id>
  
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mandy Tjew A Sin]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Published embodied terror management paper]]></title>
    <link href="http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2014/02/04/published-embodied-terror-management-paper/"/>
    <id>http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2014/02/04/published-embodied-terror-management-paper/</id>
    <published>2014-02-04T21:13:53.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-12-12T21:02:31.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Our paper titled “Embodied terror management: (Simulated) Interpersonal touch alleviates existential concerns among individuals with low self-esteem” was recently <a href="http://pss.sagepub.com/content/25/1/30" target="_blank" rel="external">published in Psychological Science</a>. It is based on some of the research on interpersonal touch that I did during my year-long internship at the VU University together with Sander Koole. I am very pleased that it made it into the world so soon. The research has been covered by a number of websites, some more accurate than others:</p>
<ul>
<li>The <a href="http://www.psychologicalscience.org/index.php/news/releases/touch-may-alleviate-existential-fears-for-people-with-low-self-esteem.html" target="_blank" rel="external">news item from the journal</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/femail/article-2509343/Cuddling-teddy-bear-ease-existential-angst-cure-fear-dying-says-new-study.html" target="_blank" rel="external">The Daily Mail</a></li>
<li>A brief mention in <a href="http://dewerelddraaitdoor.vara.nl/media/304354" target="_blank" rel="external">De Wereld Draait Door (in Dutch)</a></li>
<li>An <a href="http://www.beblissed.nl/stress-angst-of-werkloos-knuffel-een-teddybeer-knuffeltherapie/" target="_blank" rel="external">interview with Sander (in Dutch)</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>Our paper titled “Embodied terror management: (Simulated) Interpersonal touch alleviates existential concerns among individuals with low ]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Attended interdisciplinary summer school on embodied subjectivity]]></title>
    <link href="http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2013/06/16/attended-interdisciplinary-summer-school-on-embodied-subjectivity/"/>
    <id>http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2013/06/16/attended-interdisciplinary-summer-school-on-embodied-subjectivity/</id>
    <published>2013-06-16T20:10:16.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-12-21T21:44:08.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was selected (on a competitive basis) to participate in a very interesting, interdisciplinary summer school on the island of Aegina, Greece, on embodied intersubjectivity. They invited around 50 PhD students, post-docs, and other (mostly) young researchers and of course a large number of people to teach us. The presentations were given by leading researchers from the fields of experimental,developmental and social psychology, cognitive and social neuroscience, anthropology, primatology and philosophy. The programme included sessions on:</p>
<ul>
<li>1st person perspectives of embodiment</li>
<li>The embodied self in interaction with the world</li>
<li>Ontogenetic and phylogenetic perspectives on social cognition</li>
<li>Transition from 3rd person- to 2nd person perspective in social neuroscience</li>
<li>Embodying other people’s minds and bodies</li>
</ul>
<p>It was a very nice week with many interesting lectures, kind people, a beautiful location and great food. During the week, I also gave a short presentation on my work on touch and existential concerns, and I presented a poster afterwards on the same topic. Before I left Greece, I was able to sneak a very nice visit to the Acropolis and the Acropolis Museum.</p>
<div class="thumbs"><br><a href="/posts/2013/06/16/attended-interdisciplinary-summer-school-on-embodied-subjectivity/aegina_poster.jpg" title="Poster session at Aegina summer school"><img src="/posts/2013/06/16/attended-interdisciplinary-summer-school-on-embodied-subjectivity/aegina_poster.jpg"></a><br><a href="/posts/2013/06/16/attended-interdisciplinary-summer-school-on-embodied-subjectivity/aegina_location.jpg" title="Aegina summer school view"><img src="/posts/2013/06/16/attended-interdisciplinary-summer-school-on-embodied-subjectivity/aegina_location.jpg"></a><br></div>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>I was selected (on a competitive basis) to participate in a very interesting, interdisciplinary summer school on the island of Aegina, Gr]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Received NWO Mosaic grant to do PhD research]]></title>
    <link href="http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2012/11/03/received-nwo-mosaic-grant-to-do-phd-research/"/>
    <id>http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2012/11/03/received-nwo-mosaic-grant-to-do-phd-research/</id>
    <published>2012-11-03T21:29:19.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-12-21T21:51:22.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After a huge effort from Sander Koole (my internship supervisor) and I in the past half year or so, I recently <a href="http://www.nwo.nl/actueel/nieuws/2012/Moza%C3%AFek-toekenningen+bij+MaGW.html" target="_blank" rel="external">received the Mosaic grant</a> from the NWO (Netherlands Organization for Scientific Research). In January this year, I found out through a fellow student that I was eligible for this grant, but we only had a few weeks until the application deadline which included a detailed grant proposal. We had to work hard and fast to make the deadline. After making the first selection phase (41 out of 210) in February, I followed workshops to further develop my research ideas and to prepare a presentation to convince a multidisciplinary committee of professors to fund the project.</p>
<p>This summer, during my vacation, I was informed that I was one of 20 to receive the grant. Not long after, near the end of the year, NWO also held a short ceremony to award the grants in person. This was also the last time that the grant was awarded because of budget cuts, which does make it extra special. Even without applying for this grant, the last year at the VU has been a huge learning experience for me, and also very challenging, but I am very grateful that these efforts have been rewarded. It is the cherry on the cake. This is a short summary of the research project:</p>
<p>“The proposed research investigates how and why affirming feelings of belonging may improve academic achievement among ethnic minority students. The resulting insights will be used to design powerful new belongingness interventions. These interventions will be evaluated in terms of their effectiveness in closing the minority achievement gap.”</p>
<div class="thumbs"><br><a href="/posts/2012/11/03/received-nwo-mosaic-grant-to-do-phd-research/mosaic_award.jpg" title="Award ceremony NWO Mosaic grant"><img src="/posts/2012/11/03/received-nwo-mosaic-grant-to-do-phd-research/mosaic_award.jpg"></a><br></div>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>After a huge effort from Sander Koole (my internship supervisor) and I in the past half year or so, I recently <a href="http://www.nwo.nl]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Internship research mentioned in Intermediair Magazine]]></title>
    <link href="http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2012/01/04/internship-research-mentioned-in-intermediair-magazine/"/>
    <id>http://touchingresearch.com/posts/2012/01/04/internship-research-mentioned-in-intermediair-magazine/</id>
    <published>2012-01-04T21:13:53.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-12-21T20:11:05.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The research that I’m working on with Sander Koole at the VU University has found its way into the Dutch magazine Intermediair. It is an issue on ‘troost’, which is Dutch for ‘comfort’. In our research we find that interpersonal touch, but also touching soft stuffed animals, can be very comforting for people with low self-esteem.</p>
<div class="thumbs"><br><a href="/posts/2012/01/04/internship-research-mentioned-in-intermediair-magazine/intermediair.jpg" title="Intermediair"><img src="/posts/2012/01/04/internship-research-mentioned-in-intermediair-magazine/intermediair.jpg"></a><br></div>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>The research that I’m working on with Sander Koole at the VU University has found its way into the Dutch magazine Intermediair. It is an ]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>